Finding Aid for the Colin Higgins papers, ca. 1960-1987 LSC.1560
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Personal
  - [Identification, including passports; notes]. (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - [Agendas and address books, 1971-1984]. (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - [Early workshops]. (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Australia and early Stanford memorabilia. (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - [Resume and letters to agents, etc., ca. 1967]. (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - My poetry notes - completed this day of grace 7,10,58.... (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - [Poetry]. (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - [Partial list of C. Higgins' productions]. (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - [Clipping]. (Box 135, Folder 26)
  - [Quotations, proverbs]. (Box 135, Folder 28)
  - Personal poems. (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - [The sea journal]. (Box 137, Folder 12)
  - [School records and diplomas]. (Box 137, Folder 13)
  - [Collin's Australian clear school atlas, Sydney, 1954]. (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - [Birth certificate, school reports, baptism, confirmation..]. (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - [Stanford journal]. (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - [Journal, 1973, 1976, 1977]. (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - [Healing - various seminars and techniues]. (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - [Advocate magazine, interview with C. Higgins]. (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - [Clippings and Diversion magazine]. (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - [Identification cards (director's guild....), address book]. (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - [Who's who in Hollywood, 1959-1962]. (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - [Who's who in Hollywood, 1963-1966]. (Box 142, Folder 6)
- Peter Brook
  - Peter Brook. (Box 129, Folder 12)
- Phantom
  - [The phantom: Desert justice () and Girl of mystery (1939)]. (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - The Phantom, treatment. (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - [The Phantom's profile]. (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - [Phantom comic books, 7 items, ca. 1963-1967]. (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - [Phantom comic books, 9 items, ca. 1963-1974]. (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - [Phantom newspaper comic strips, ca. 1940s]. (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - [The Phantom comic book, ca. 1947]. (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - [The Phantom, photocopied comic book and correspondence]. (Box 128, Folder 8)
- Photographs
  - [Photographs of C. Higgins, ca. 1960]. (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - [Photographs of C. Higgins with President Carter and Senator Ed. Kennedy]. (Box 138, Folder 6)
- Plans, Posters
  - Oversize folder. (Box 149)
  - Oversize folder. (Box 148)
- Paramount Films, Pre-1947
  - Purchased by Universal. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Private Benjamin
  - Screenplay - third draft, September 24, 197_. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Private Henley Goes to War
  - [Private Henley goes to war, a.k.a. Another Hero, story]. (Box 135, Folder 31)
- Publicity
  - [The Fine Line, UCLA College of Fina Arts, interviews C. Higgins]. (Box 109, Folder 1)
- Reminiscences
  - [Reminiscences, monologue]. (Box 135, Folder 24)
- Research, Ideas
  - Plot ideas. (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Quotes. (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Script ideas. (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Workshop - UCLA - lines, stories, etc. (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - [Thoughts on Comedy]. (Box 112, Folder 11)
- Retreat
  - [Retreat - visuals and sound]. (Box 135, Folder 33)
- Rusty
  - Notes, - With notes on legal pad., January 9, 1987 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - [Proposed television file]. (Box 82, Folder 5)
- Ruth Gordon, Thornton Wilder
  - Postcards from Wilder to Gordon, Higgins' notes, clippings; Higgins met Wilder at the Plaza Hotel., February 19, 1974 (Box 97, Folder 7)
- School
  - [Criticism]. (Box 135, Folder 12)
- Scripts
  - [Stanford Gaieties, 3 scripts]. (Box 112, Folder 9)
- Seems Like Old Times
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon - revised 1st draft, January 1980. (Box 56, Folder 1)
- Silver Streak
  - [1 poster]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, fan letter. (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Promotional brochure -20th Century-Fox for Seventy-Seven. (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Publicity - reviews, advertisements. (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - [Bound volume containing 2 scripts, stills, ephemera]. (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - [Silver Streak script, Marty Randolf version, March 26, 1976]. (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - [Silver Streak script,, no.25]; My first rewrite for Fox., March 1, 1976 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - [Silver Streak script,, no.55]; Final script by me without pressures.., March 24, 1976 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - [Silver Streak script, master]; Signed copy. (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - [Super Chief script]. (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - [Silver Streak, promotion]. (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - [Silver Streak research, travel]. (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - [Super Chief script with corrections]; C. Higgins' name is misspelled. (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - [Super Chief story outline and research]. (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - [Super Chief script]. (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - [Super Chief script]. (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - [Super Chief story outline, with corrections]; Signed by C. Higgins. (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - [Silver Streak press kit]. (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - [Silver Streak ephemera and writers' awards program]. (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - [Silver Streak prop newspaper]. (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Silver Streak papers. (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Silver Streak final script with all changes, March 26, 1976. (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Silver Streak script, widescreen, November 23, 1976. (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - [Silver Streak(?) prop newspaper; certificate American cinematique]. (Box 141, Folder 8)
  - Laser video disk. (Box 147, Folder 3)
- Silver Streak (Super Chief)
  - Participation settlement agreement and correspondence. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Cast and crew sheets. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Contracts - deal memo. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Earnings. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Syd Field's book - screenplay. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Novelization. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook [loose pages]. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Story outline - 2 copies. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - First draft - Super Chief. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Revised draft - March 26, 1976. (Box 40, Folder 1, 2)
  - Partial script. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Revised draft, - with revised pages, March 26, 1976 April 2, 1976. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Corespondence, 1978. (Box 40, Folder 5)
- Silver Streak - Foul Play
  - Videocassette rankings, 1981. (Box 40, Folder 6)
- Sing a Song of Murder
  - [Sing a song of murder, script]. (Box 136, Folder 4)
- Stand-in
  - Outline - Dustin Hoffman and Murray Schisgal, January 11, 1983. (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Sunshine Boys
  - Final draft - by Neil Simon, December 20, 1972. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Screenplay by Neil Simon - first draft, September 1974. (Box 52, Folder 8)
- Swanee
  - Pilot script by Lawrence J. Cohen and Fred Freeman, August 30, 1978. (Box 56, Folder 6)
- Ten
  - [The ten - plot, notes]. (Box 129, Folder 8)
- The Best Time
  - [The best time, script for film]; Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 135, Folder 3)
- Theodore
  - [Theodore, second treatment, November 13, 1972]. (Box 129, Folder 10)
- Time for Revenge
  - Breakdown and notes, 1983. (Box 82, Folder 6)
- Time on a Train
  - [Time on a train, #1 action]; Typescript with professor's comments. (Box 135, Folder 5)
- Titus Andronicus
  - [Screenplay - adapted by Colin Higgins]. (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - [Screenplay by Colin Higgins - with holograph notes]. (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - [Screenplay]. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - [Screenplay]. (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - [Screenplay]. (Box 83, Folder 3, 4)
  - [Research]. (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Work notes. (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - First draft, April 7, 1972. (Box 83, Folder 7)
- Tootsie
  - Screenplay by Larry Gelbart, - newer; With revisions, March 8, 1982 through August 27, 1982. (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Treatment by Robert Kaufman, - 26pp., April 20, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Treatment by Larry Gelbart, - 27pp. - older., September 24, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Would I lie to you aka Tootsie, - revisions; Screenplay by Larry Gelbart, 139pp., April 10, 1981 August 3, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Script - by Larry Gelbart, February 20, 1981. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Third revision, - Screenplay by Larry Gelbart; 128pp., January 12, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - 2nd revision, - Screenplay by Larry Gelbart; 158pp., December 14, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Screenplay by Murray Schisgal, - 120pp., May 19, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Script - 2nd revision, June 22, 1980. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Revised pages by Murray Schisgal, April 12, 1982 August 2, 1982. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Screenplay by Elaine May - 132pp. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Screenplay by Elaine May - 145pp. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Screenplay by Robert Kaufman - 1st draft, - 118pp., January 25, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 6)
- Trainer
  - Story and screenplay by Clarke L'Amoreaux - with memo, May 22, 1983. (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Story and screenplay by Clarke L'Amoreaux. (Box 57, Folder 3)
- Twins
  - Notes and outline. (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - [Outline of Act 1 and letter ]; Also known as Family Business.., May 3, 1984 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Contract. (Box 83, Folder 10)
- Two Weeks in London
  - [Memos and outline of story]. (Box 83, Folder 11)
- UCLA Film School
  - [Best of UCLA film school, vol.1,, C. Higgins host - poster]., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Unidentified Plans
  - [Stage 14, 1 item]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Security Pacific building, 1 item]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Universal Bungalow
  - [Plans, 28 items]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Plans, 19 items]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Plans, ca. 50 items]. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Vietnam War Movie
  - [Clippings and notes]. (Box 84, Folder 1)
- Voting day in 8th Admin. Co.
  - [Voting day in 8th Admin Co, script]. (Box 135, Folder 25)
- Washington Trip
  - May 1979. (Box 84, Folder 2, 3)
- Washington, D.C.
  - Dixie. (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Jane. (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Verna. (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Durning. (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Contacts / Hotels. (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Fourth of July. (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Tom Mankiewicz. (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Notes - Senate. (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Notes. (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Outlines. (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Lobbyists. (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Plot points / scandals / themes. (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Scandals. (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Renting apartment. (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Research. (Box 86, Folder 1-3)
  - Preliminary, July 11, 1986. (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Scripts - preliminary, July 31, 1986. (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - [Screenplay - drafts, outlines, scenes] (5 folders). (Box 86, Folder 6, Box 87)
  - Wordstar script, October 14, 1986. (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Red, white and blue - screenplay by Colin Higgins,; Story by Colin Higgins and Tom Mankiewicz., October 15, 1986 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Red, white and blue,; CH on cover., October 20, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Untitled Washington project - screenplay by Colin Higgins, November 7, 1986. (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Red, white and blue - script, October 14, 1986. (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Red, white and blue - script, October 15, 1986. (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Red, white and blue - script, October 16, 1986. (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Untitled Washington project - script, October 20, 1986. (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Untitled Washington project - script, November 7, 1986. (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Untitled Washington project - script, November 11, 1986. (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Untitled Washington project - script, November 11, 1986. (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Titles - out. (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Travel. (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - White House movie. (Box 89, Folder 5)
- What the hell is PIO?
  - [What the hell is PIO?, script]. (Box 135, Folder 22)
- Wizard's Fool
  - Casting. (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Deal memo. (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Script author's notes. (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Script comments. (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Notes - tapes. (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Notes - script 1. (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Notes - script 2. (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Notes - handwritten. (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Research (2 folders). (Box 90, Folder 1, 2)
  - Notes for production (budget, sets, day-out-of-days ... ). (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - First draft, - screenplay by Colin Higgins., September 21, 1984 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - First draft, - 4 copies., September 26, 1984 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Second draft, - 2 copies., January 8, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Third draft, - 3 copies; 1 copy with special effects marked., January 28, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Third draft, - 130pp., February 1, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Third draft, - 129pp. - 2 copies., February 1, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Fourth draft - original, April 7, 1985. (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Fourth draft, - 3 copies., April 7, 1985 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Fifth draft - original, July 28, 1985. (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Fifth draft, August 8, 1985. (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Fifth draft, July 28, 1985. (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Fifth draft - original, August 8, 1985. (Box 92, Folder 5)
- The Would-be Volpone
  - [The would-be volpone, a critical essay....]. (Box 135, Folder 20)
- Worst of Friends
  - [Between Friends - screenplay, outline, correspondence]. (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - [Screenplay - 2 copies]. (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - [Screenplay by David Greewalt and Jim Kouf, ]; Story by Jim Kouf., July 9, 1986 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - [Screenplay by David Greenwalt and Jim Kouf, July 9, 1986]. (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - [Screenplay, June 30, 1986]. (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - [Screenplay, July 2, 1986]. (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - [Screenplay, - Hodgepodge Version]; For Colin Higgins eyes only.., January 22, 1987 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Rewrite, April 9, 1987. (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - [Screenplay, April 30, 1987]. (Box 94, Folder 3)